<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2010-2011, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology Transfer
  at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Notes</title>
    <author email="Paul.Ramirez@jpl.nasa.gov">Paul Ramirez</author>
    <author email="Sean.Hardman@jpl.nasa.gov">Sean Hardman</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Release Notes">
      <p>The purpose of this section is to provide a description of a Registry component release including any impact that the new or modified capabilities will have on the Discipline Nodes or the PDS user community. A somewhat itemized list of changes for each component can be found on the Release Changes page for that component.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 1.0.0">
      <p>This release of Registry is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-2.0.0.html">2.0.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Added support for a PostgreSQL database in the Registry Core and Service components.</li>
        <li>Added the ability to generate database schema from the model classes in the Registry Core and Service components.</li>
        <li>Added support for browsing associations, packages, services, events, schemes, and classification nodes in the Registry UI component.</li>
        <li>Cleaned up the interface with respect to scrolling and window behavior in the Registry UI component.</li>
        <li>Update the contents of the Object Type pull-down menu to conform with the supported types from the data model in the Registry UI component.</li>
        <li>Introduced the Python-based API to the Registry Service.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The liens for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Query support has been improved but is still case sensitive.</li>
        <li>The Federation and Registry objects have not been addressed yet.</li>
        <li>Need to generate a log file that conforms to the Report Service format.</li>
        <li>Need to add support for artifact registration in the Registry UI component.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.7.0">
      <p>This release of Registry is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-1.2.0.html">1.2.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the assessment of the PDS4 standards and the system components to date. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Added support for package registration allowing actions like approval and deletion to be applied to all members of a package.</li>
        <li>Added support for replication from one registry instance to another.</li>
        <li>Enhanced query support for auditable events.</li>
        <li>Moved the end points up one level to remove the redundant /registry from the path.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The liens for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Query support has been improved but is still case sensitive.</li>
        <li>The Federation and Registry objects have not been addressed yet.</li>
        <li>Need to generate a log file that conforms to the Report Service format.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.6.0">
      <p>This release of Registry is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-1.1.0.html">1.1.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the assessment of the PDS4 standards and the system components to date. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>The core functionality was moved from this package to the registry-core package to better satisfy JAR dependencies from other projects.</li>
        <li>Added additional support for Classifications in the registry.</li>
        <li>Added a configuration endpoint allowing the configuration file generated from the data model to be processed in one action.</li>
        <li>Added support for a RegistryPackage object to support batch operations.</li>
        <li>Added additional support for Service registrations.</li>
        <li>Modifications to support better alignment with the ebXML registry specification.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The liens for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Query support has been improved but is still case sensitive.</li>
        <li>The Federation and Registry objects have not been addressed yet.</li>
        <li>Need to generate a log file that conforms to the Report Service format.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.5.0">
      <p>This release of Registry is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-1.0.0.html">1.0.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the assessment of the PDS4 standards. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Added support for registering Service and Classification objects.</li>
        <li>Added support for deleting Products and Associations.</li>
        <li>Added an interface for retrieving Auditable Events.</li>
        <li>Updated the status message to include counts of registered objects.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The liens for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Exception handling at this stage of development is minimal. Many error conditions have not yet been mapped to HTTP error codes.</li>
        <li>Query support is case sensitive and not fully implemented for each object type.</li>
        <li>Not all aspects of JSON support have been implemented.</li>
        <li>The Federation and Registry objects have not been addressed yet.</li>
        <li>Need to generate a log file that conforms to the Report Service format.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.4.0">
      <p>This release of Registry is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-0.1.0.html">0.1.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the demonstration at the Management Council Face-to-Face meeting in August 2010. This initial release of the service provides the capability to register and browse data products and their associations.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

