<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2010, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology Transfer
  at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Notes</title>
    <author email="Paul.Ramirez@jpl.nasa.gov">Paul Ramirez</author>
    <author email="Sean.Hardman@jpl.nasa.gov">Sean Hardman</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Release Notes">
      <p>The purpose of this section is to provide a description of a Registry Service release including any impact that the new or modified capabilities will have on the Discipline Nodes or the PDS user community. If viewing the web-based version of this document, a somewhat itemized list of changes for each release can be found on the <a href="../changes-report.html">Release Changes</a> page.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.5.0">
      <p>This release of the Registry Service is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../../release/index-1.0.0.html">1.0.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the assessment of the PDS4 standards. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Added support for registering Service and Classification objects.</li>
        <li>Added support for deleting Products and Associations.</li>
        <li>Added an interface for retrieving Auditable Events.</li>
        <li>Updated the status message to include counts of registered objects.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The liens for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Exception handling at this stage of development is minimal. Many error conditions have not yet been mapped to HTTP error codes.</li>
        <li>Query support is case sensitive and not fully implemented for each object type.</li>
        <li>Not all aspects of JSON support have been implemented.</li>
        <li>The Federation and Registry objects have not been addressed yet.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.4.0">
      <p>This release of the Registry Service is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../../release/index-0.1.0.html">0.1.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the demonstration at the Management Council Face-to-Face meeting in August 2010. This initial release of the service provides the capability to register and browse data products and their associations.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

