<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2011-2012, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology Transfer
  at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.
    
  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Changes</title>
    <author email="Jordan.H.Padams@jpl.nasa.gov">Jordan Padams</author>
  </properties>
  
  <body>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="TBD" description="This release of the Search Core is a component of the integrated release 3.1.0 of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2012-09-30" description="This release of the Search Core is a component of the integrated release 3.0.0 of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-100">
        Refactored the Search Protocol and XML Response Writer out of the search-core and into search-service. Also moved Solr index scripts from search-service to search-core and updated the scripts to use absolute paths. Updated pom files accordingly to reflect changes in dependencies from refactoring of Solr stuff.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add" issue="PDS-102">
        Created PDSDateConvert class to handle conversions of PDS4-compliant date/time values into Solr-compliant date/time values.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated CLI by requiring registry URL to be specified, a new flag to specify a configuration directory, and a new flag to specify Search Service Home.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Renamed several classes to use PDS4 terminology (i.e ProductClass.java and SearchFields.java).
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated Solr document parser class to populate unknown/null date/time fields with values.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated Solr Indexer to create multiple solr-index.xml depending on a specified threshold of index documents for Solr Index file. This coincides with changes to the solr-post script, alleviating issues with Java Heap during XSLT transformations prior to posting to the Solr Web App.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated PSA Config to capture more information from data in the registry. May be temporary fix until more data is available. Includes data_object_type and mission_start/stop_date.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Modified references to Search Service Home throughout application and documentation in an effort to eliminate confusion between the path used in Search Core versus the path specified in the Search Service installation. Changed Search Service Home to Search Home, where applicable.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated Installation and Operation documentation to reflect the changes in tool functionality.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="fix">
        Fixed bug in ProductClass class to set default version to 1.0 when associated lidvid does not contain a version.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.3.0" date="2012-06-11" description="This release of the Search Core is a component of the integrated release 2.2.0 of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Added command-line option to specify number of queried records.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Updated the configuration to reflect to changes in slot names, in accordance with changes made by harvest.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Refactored Registry Extractor, Solr Indexer, and PDS Indexer to reflect changes in the registry-core client.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="remove">
        Removed the parent project's Release Notes document. This document now serves as the single source for this component's release changes.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.2.0" date="2012-01-31" description="This release of the Search Core is a component of the integrated release 2.1.0 of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="shardman" type="update">
        Cleaned up the documentation and removed the PDF generation feature.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.0" date="2011-11-09" description="This release of the Search Core is a component of the integrated release 2.0.0 of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Initial implementation of PDS search protocol request handler.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Refactored implementation of Registry Data Search prototype to work with registry-core v1.0.0.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Command-line interface to run Registry Extractor, Solr Indexer, and PDS Indexer.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
