<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2011-2018, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology Transfer
  at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Changes</title>
    <author email="Jordan.H.Padams@jpl.nasa.gov">Jordan Padams</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <release version="1.13.0" date="2018-09-28" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 9.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
    </release>

    <release version="1.12.1" date="2018-05-01" description="This release of Search Core is a component of an interim point build for the Search components. This is an operational release of the components to date.">
    </release>

    <release version="1.12.0" date="2018-03-30" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 8.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="shardman" type="update" issue="PDS-528">
        Nixed the pds3/archiveinfo.xml config file since it was essentially duplicate of context.xml. Also updated the pds3/context.xml and pds4/context.xml files to include investigation, instrument_host and instrument fields.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.11.0" date="2017-09-29" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 8.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
    </release>

    <release version="1.10.0" date="2017-03-31" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 7.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update" issue="PDS-492">
        Updated to improve the appearance of Archive Page products in search results.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="add" issue="PDS-494">
        Added support for Product_Document to be returned in search results.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.9.0" date="2016-09-30" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 7.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
    </release>

    <release version="1.8.1" date="2016-07-12" description="This release of Search Core is a component of an interim point build for the Search components. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="shardman" type="add" issue="PDS-429">
        Added configuration files to support indexing of Product_Service products in order to support the Tool Registry. Also updated all of the configuration files to consistently populate the data_product_type field.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="update">
        Updated the documentation to address issues SW-19, SW-20 and SW-21.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.8.0" date="2016-03-31" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 6.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update" issue="PDS-370">
        Updated to improve handling of date/time fields.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="update">
        Cleaned up the configuration files and included extraction of file_ref_* fields and added support for indexing Product_Document products.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="update">
        Updated the JRE requirement to 1.7 in the Installation document.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.7.0" date="2015-09-30" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 6.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
    </release>

    <release version="1.6.0" date="2015-03-31" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 5.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add" issue="PDS-335">
        Create new configs for Product_Attribute_Definition and Product_Class_Definition products.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-363">
        Added PDS_Affiliate fields to PDS4 context product configuration.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated error handling to be more descriptive when a search core run fails.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.5.0" date="2014-09-30" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 5.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-277">
        Updated configurations to consistently include data_class and product_class slots for all product types.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-286">
        Updated ProductClass to include new SlotFilter for version_id = latest. Updated dataset.xml to include version_id. Add new test to ProductClassTest.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-294">
        Updated the configurations to only include products where status is "Approved". Updated a couple tests (albeit not all that useful) to include references to this.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-301">
        Updated core config schema to allow for specification of both output string or registry path in the configurations. The registry path will be used by default, unless it is not found. Updated pds4 context config to use this functionality to look for resource_url for the resLocation, otherwise default to the ds-view/viewContext page.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.4.1" date="2014-06-20" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 4.1.1 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-261">
        Added external_reference_text to all configs.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-262">
        Updated XSD and JAXB classes to allow for multiple registry paths in core configs. This handles the context products that require the software to look in two different places for the same search field. Removed all Product_Context configs for the specific context products. Create new generic context product config to add in all context products. 
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.4.0" date="2014-03-31" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 4.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-229">
        Created new core configs for all of the specific PDS4 context products, which include the new SlotFilters. Also updated ProductClass to respond to updates to RegistryResults API, including the generation of Association and Slot Filters.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update" issue="PDS-253">
        Updated Unix shell script and Windows batch files to provide a more user friendly message when JAVA_HOME is not set in the environment.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-255">
        Updated all core configs with new search_id field. Also generated OutputString and OutputStringFormat classes from the core-config.xsd to allow for specification of the format required for the output String. Previous implementation automatically URL encoded the string.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-256">
        Created new archiveinfo.xml config for PDS4 resources.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Update documentation to take change from initial-index-pdsen to search-core-pdsen.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated PSA data set config to use localhost. Updated PDS4 config to only refer to registry-pds4 and no longer refer to registry-atm.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.3.0" date="2013-09-30" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 4.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-144">
        Get all .xml files in the given config directory instead of requiring product-classes.txt to be specified.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-154">
        Allow for unlimited 'jumps' for associations to be specified (i.e. instrument_host_ref.instrument_ref.data_set_ref.node_ref.agengy_ref.alternate_id will get agency).
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-173">
        Completed patch for use with Solr 4, including updates to pom dependencies and Indexer.java.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-177">
        Updated PDS config files to point to relative instead of absolute URL to resolve issue with domain specificity.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-189">
        Updated command-line options and property keys to allow for specification of primary and secondary registries; also update XSD to allow for inclusion of 'DataSources' which can then be set with primary/secondary 'priority' and DataSource type (i.e. registry) as well as the option to 'append' the new sources to the current list specified via command-line/property file, or to overwrite.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Created new logging and stats classes to maintain the missing slot/associations/etc.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated unit tests to reflect changes from PDS-189.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Leveraged decorator pattern for Extrinsic Objects to allow for extension of the objects that come back from the Registry. Allows for methods like getLidvid, getSlotValues, etc.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Refactored RegistryAttributes class to be an enum to better handle Registry attributes.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated unit tests to test new classes/methods.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated core configs to work with XSD.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated software to use XML schema to specify configurations for different products. Introduced core-config.xsd.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Removed Indexer and ProfileParser classes that have been deprecated from use and no longer have a use. Updated Launcher to remove reference to these classes.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Cleaned up assembly.xml to use correct syntax for recursive include.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated SearchCorePDS3Test to run against only 5 data sets instead of 1000 to improve deployment performance.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated solr-post script to use awk instead of gawk for systems that do not have gawk installed.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated OPUS description in search-tools.xml.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated documentation to include info on configurations.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.2.1" date="2013-06-21" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 3.1.1 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated EN-specific documentation to be very explicit with exact steps for running index.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.2.0" date="2013-03-31" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 3.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add" issue="PDS-138">
        Created Search Service config files for Bundle, Collection, and Context PDS4 products.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated config file directories to reflect future installations (pds/pds3, pds/pds4, psa/pds3).
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated PDS3 product configurations to remove all search fields named mission_* with investigation_* to meet with PDS4 model.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated unit test classes to reflect changes in config file directories.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Created initial-index-pdsen script that will create index specific to PDS Engineering node, including flags for PDS3, PDS4, and PSA data products.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.1" date="2012-11-14" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release supporting the deployment of the system at the Engineering Node and includes updates for issues discovered during deployment.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Created ops-index script to rsync data from remote machine in order for operational use.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Created env-vars scripts to allow for specification of all environment variables. Minimizes potential human error.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-132">
        Updated module documentation to handle more potential errors from installation.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated in-line documentation in all core Bash scripts for running the index.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.0" date="2012-11-09" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release supporting the deployment of the system at the Engineering Node.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add" issue="PDS-119">
        Created new Archive Information configuration file to include mission resources in search results.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-119">
        Updated ProductClass and SearchField classes to include handling of a name-based query of the registry in order to return Archive Information.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-121">
        Updated hierarchy to include new agency facet.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-121">
        Updated data set config to include new agency_name field.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Fixed bug in solr-post script where the search tools were not being included in the index.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2012-09-30" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 3.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add" issue="PDS-102">
        Created PDSDateConvert class to handle conversions of PDS4-compliant date/time values into Solr-compliant date/time values.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update" issue="PDS-100">
        Refactored the Search Protocol and XML Response Writer out of the search-core and into search-service. Also moved Solr index scripts from search-service to search-core and updated the scripts to use absolute paths. Updated pom files accordingly to reflect changes in dependencies from refactoring of Solr stuff.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated CLI by requiring registry URL to be specified, a new flag to specify a configuration directory, and a new flag to specify Search Service Home.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Renamed several classes to use PDS4 terminology (i.e ProductClass.java and SearchFields.java).
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated Solr document parser class to populate unknown/null date/time fields with values.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated Solr Indexer to create multiple solr-index.xml depending on a specified threshold of index documents for Solr Index file. This coincides with changes to the solr-post script, alleviating issues with Java Heap during XSLT transformations prior to posting to the Solr Web App.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated PSA Config to capture more information from data in the registry. THis may be a temporary fix until more data is available. Includes data_object_type and mission_start/stop_date.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Modified references to Search Service Home throughout application and documentation in an effort to eliminate confusion between the path used in Search Core versus the path specified in the Search Service installation. Changed Search Service Home to Search Home, where applicable.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Updated Installation and Operation documentation to reflect the changes in tool functionality.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="fix">
        Fixed bug in ProductClass class to set default version to 1.0 when associated lidvid does not contain a version.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.3.0" date="2012-06-11" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 2.2.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Added command-line option to specify number of queried records.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Updated the configuration to reflect to changes in slot names, in accordance with changes made by harvest.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="update">
        Refactored Registry Extractor, Solr Indexer, and PDS Indexer to reflect changes in the registry-core client.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="remove">
        Removed the parent project's Release Notes document. This document now serves as the single source for this component's release changes.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.2.0" date="2012-01-31" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 2.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="shardman" type="update">
        Cleaned up the documentation and removed the PDF generation feature.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.0" date="2011-11-09" description="This release of Search Core is a component of the integrated release 2.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Initial implementation of PDS search protocol request handler.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Refactored implementation of Registry Data Search prototype to work with registry-core v1.0.0.
      </action>
      <action dev="jpadams" type="add">
        Command-line interface to run Registry Extractor, Solr Indexer, and PDS Indexer.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
