<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2010-2011, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology Transfer
  at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Changes</title>
    <author email="Paul.Ramirez@jpl.nasa.gov">Paul Ramirez</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="TBD" description="This release of the Registry Service is a component of the integrated release 2.0.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
    </release>

    <release version="0.7.0" date="2011-08-29" description="This release of the Registry Service is a component of the integrated release 1.2.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-14: End point to remove package members and update the status of all package members. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-30: Allow PUT operation to create/update a Service object.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-32: Added end point to manage ExternalLinks which can be used to tie registry contents to URLs that exist outside the registry. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        PDS-37: Moved registry end points one level removing the redundant /registry from the path.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        PDS-38: Registry version now comes back as part of the report end point.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-39: Added end point to allow for replication from a remote registry. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        End point to page through packages.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        Enchanced Auditable Event end point to allow for better filtering. Now supports eventStart, eventEnd, and requestId. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.6.0" date="2011-03-25" description="This release of the Registry Service is a component of the integrated release 1.1.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-3: Ability to page through all services. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        PDS-7: Mapped Product to ExtrinsicObject to align better with information model for registry. Moved all interfaces that ended in product(s) to extrinsic(s). Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-8: Allow a set of Classifications to be associated with a given registry object. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-13: End point responses for /registry-service and /registry-service/registry. This merely respond to GET requests for now with link headers pointing to the sub-resources. 
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-16: Configuration end point to pass in classification schemes and nodes as one XML file. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-19: Defined RegistryPackage as an intrinsic object. Acts merely as a collection of registered objects through the use of Associations. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-20: Added ExternalIdentifier support for registered objects. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-22: Include delete operation for Classifications delete. Inherited from registry-core.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Added improved support for registration and retrieval of service registrations.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Support for MySQL back end. Provided documentation for configuration and property file configuration.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.5.0" date="2010-10-31" description="This release of the Registry Service is a component of the integrated release 1.0.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Ability to deal with Services. This required the addition of Service Bindings and Specification Links as well.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Ability to deal with Classifications. This required the addition of Classification Schemes and Nodes as well.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Interface to retrieve Auditable Events.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Ability to delete products.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Ability to delete associations.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        Updated registry status information to include counts on the number of managed items.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        Refactored any list response to simply be a RegistryResponse instead of a PagedResponse.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        Added a default sort order on slots so they come back in a fixed order on repeated requests. The default order now is their generated id.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        Updated persistence layer to be more flexible and require less change as we add new types of RegistryObject's. For example, instead of having saveProduct and saveAssociation there is now a unified saveRegistryObject.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="fix">
        Slot values that were extremely large would truncate. Now they map to @Lob with a length of max integer.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="fix">
        Convert from using userVersion to using versionId for externally tracked versions. Switch to versionName instead of version to align with model.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.4.0" date="2010-08-25" description="This release of the Registry Service is a component of the integrated release 0.1.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Registry Client API support of filtering on products and associations.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Registry client support of ssoToken set for interaction with service.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Filtering for associations within the registry. Same restrictions that apply to the product filtering.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.3-dev" date="2010-07-26" description="This release of the Registry Service supports integration with the Registry User Interface developed at Ames.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Added basic registry client API to support interface development. This is a Java API that abstracts away the URL mappings and serves back Java objects.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Filtering for registered products. This supports the basic retrieve a set of products given some criteria. Is not a full blown search API as that will be dealt with by the Search service.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Documentation integration and updates for service interface. Provides examples and is generated as part of the build.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.2-dev-RC" date="2010-07-06" description="This release of the Registry Service supports integration with the Registry User Interface developed at Ames.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Support for registration of Products.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Support for registration of Associations.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Allow changing of registry object status.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Support for auditable events. This allows us to track the changes made to registry objects.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Added support for persistence to Derby DB for registry back end. This was done using the Java Persistence library.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Spring integration to support injection of components that make up the system. This allows for extensibility by placing how the system is put together in configuration rather than code.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Pluggable identifier generation.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Pluggable version generation.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Support for basic navigation through URLs to registry objects.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
