<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2010-2012, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology Transfer
  at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Notes</title>
    <author email="Michael.Cayanan@jpl.nasa.gov">Michael Cayanan</author>
    <author email="Sean.Hardman@jpl.nasa.gov">Sean Hardman</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Release Notes">
      <p>The purpose of this document is to provide a description of a Harvest Tool release including any impact that the new or modified capabilities will have on the Discipline Nodes or the PDS user community. An itemized list of changes for each release can be found in the <a href="../changes-report.html">Release Changes</a> document.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 1.1.0">
      <p>This release of the Harvest Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-2.1.0.html">2.1.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Made a number of modification to support changes in the PDS4 data model for this release.</li>
        <li>Added the ability to specify the slot name in the registry for an element extracted from a PDS label.</li>
        <li>Added some new command-line options for targets, a configuration file and a PDS3 directory.</li>
        <li>Cleaned up the documentation.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where the tool complained about the keystore password not being specified.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 1.0.0">
      <p>This release of the Harvest Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-2.0.0.html">2.0.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Added support for providing access URLs for registered products.</li>
        <li>Modified to convert all cross references from PDS product labels into slots for a registered product instead of registering a separate association for each one.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where the directory path was not determined correctly for document products.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.4.0">
      <p>This release of the Harvest Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-1.2.0.html">1.2.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the assessment of the PDS4 standards and the system components to date. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Added support for registering PDS3 products with proxy labels.</li>
        <li>Added the capability to perform file object registration enabling file-level tracking.</li>
        <li>Modified to represent LID-based references as slots instead of associations.</li>
        <li>Modified to register a package with each run enabling support for actions like approval and deletion to be applied to all members of a package in the Registry Service.</li>
        <li>Modified to keep pace with changes occurring in the PDS4 data model, the Registry Service interface and the Security Service.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.3.0">
      <p>This release of the Harvest Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-1.1.0.html">1.1.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the assessment of the PDS4 standards and the system components to date. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Added the capability to validate products prior to registration.</li>
        <li>Added the capability to execute the tool as a daemon.</li>
        <li>Modified and made more robust the handling of association registrations.</li>
        <li>Modified to keep pace with changes occurring in the PDS4 data model.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The liens for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Needs to support registration of PDS3 products.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.2.0">
      <p>This release of the Harvest Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-1.0.0.html">1.0.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the assessment of the PDS4 standards. The new or modified capabilities for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Added support for namespaces within product labels.</li>
        <li>Added support to register Bundle products including the Collection products that they reference.</li>
        <li>Updated to support the latest changes to the PDS4 model.</li>
        <li>Updated to support table-formatted Collection products.</li>
        <li>Updated the log contents to include summary information and product GUIDs.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The liens for this release are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Needs to support validation of products prior to registration.</li>
        <li>Does not yet support recognition of products that have already been registered versus newly discovered products. This is required to function in a true crawler scenario.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.1.0">
      <p>This release of the Harvest Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../release/index-0.1.0.html">0.1.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the demonstration at the Management Council Face-to-Face meeting in August 2010. This initial release of the tool provides the capability to crawl a data collection, discover data products and register them in a target Registry Service.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

