<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2011, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology Transfer
  at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Notes</title>
    <author email="Jordan.Padams@jpl.nasa.gov">Jordan Padams</author>
    <author email="Sean.Hardman@jpl.nasa.gov">Sean Hardman</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Release Notes">
      <p>The purpose of this section is to provide a description of a Generate Tool release including any impact that the new or modified capabilities will have on the Discipline Nodes or the PDS user community. If viewing the web-based version of this document, a somewhat itemized list of changes for each release can be found on the <a href="../changes-report.html">Release Changes</a> page.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.3.0">
      <p>This release of the Generate Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../../release/index-2.1.0.html">2.1.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.2.0">
      <p>This release of the Generate Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../../release/index-2.0.0.html">2.0.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date. This release is a roll up of the 0.1.1 intermediate release and includes some documentation updates.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="Release 0.1.0">
      <p>This release of the Generate Tool is a component of the integrated release <a href="../../../release/index-1.2.0.html">1.2.0</a> of the PDS 2010 System. This release is intended as a prototype release in support of the assessment of the PDS4 standards and the system components to date. This release includes initial capabilities for generating PDS4 product labels from PDS3 product labels.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

