<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2009-2014, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology
  Transfer at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Changes</title>
    <author email="Sean.Hardman@jpl.nasa.gov">Sean Hardman</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <release version="1.7.0" date="TBD" description="TBD">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Modified the Catalog Tool to use the Product_Volume_PDS3 product's LID as the base LID for product repository products of Housekeeping, Person, Reference, and Target.    
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update" issue="PDS-227">
        Corrected an issue where catalog files that are not registered as context products were having their file objects versioned and re-registered.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-228">
        Corrected an issue reading data set map projection catalog files.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-231">
        Corrected an issue where the same instrument host reference is replicated for each instrument reference.    
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update" issue="PDS-248">
        Added file type and mime type slots to file repository products.  
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.6.1" date="2013-12-02" description="This release of the Catalog Tool is a component of the integrated release 4.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
        <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-201">
          Corrected to capture instrument host reference only from data set catalog file.
        </action>
        <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-202">
          Added support for map projection catalog pointer.
        </action>
        <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-203">
          Corrected the tool to strip leading and trailing white space from keyword values.
        </action>
        <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-204">
          Corrected to generate correct investigation reference when mission name spans multiple lines.
        </action>
        <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-205">
          Corrected this issue by addressing PDS-201.
        </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.6.0" date="2013-09-30" description="This release of the Catalog Tool is a component of the integrated release 4.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-163">
        Corrected the tool to not re-ingest when a catalog file hasn't changed.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Corrected the target_ref slot was getting populated twice.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.5.1" date="2013-06-21" description="This release of the Catalog Tool is a component of the integrated release 3.1.1 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update" issue="PDS-170">
         Added two slots (product_class and information_model_version) to each product that the Catalog Tool registers. Also modified to generate all URNs in lowercase and to generate the Target URN as follows: urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:&lt;target_type&gt;.&lt;target_name&gt;.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-171">
         Corrected the tool to not crash when a software catalog file is referenced in the VOLDESC.CAT.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.5.0" date="2013-03-31" description="This release of the Catalog Tool is a component of the integrated release 3.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-123">
        Corrected bad output message when executing without mode selection.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="add">
        Added to support for the DATA_SET_HOUSEKEEPING catalog object.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="add">
        Added to support for the DATA_SET_RELEASE catalog object.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.4.0" date="2012-09-30" description="This release of the Catalog Tool is a component of the integrated release 3.0.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-87">
        Updated the dependency list in the POM to grab the correct commons-collections version.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-88">
        Corrected bad output message when voldesc points to a missing file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix" issue="PDS-89">
        Displays informative error message when a bad password is entered.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.3.0" date="2012-06-11" description="This release of the Catalog Tool is a component of the integrated release 2.2.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date.">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update">
        Updated the reference type mapping.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update" issue="PDS-52">
        Updated to accept VOLDESC.CATs with multiple values for *_CATALOG.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.2.0" date="2012-01-31" description="This release of the Catalog Tool is a component of the integrated release 2.1.0 of the PDS4 System. This is an operational release of the system components to date. ">
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update">
        Modified the tool to register catalog file information with the Registry Service instead of the PDS catalog database.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="update">
        Renamed the tool from Catalog Ingest Tool to just Catalog Tool and copied the source under the 2010 tree.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="update">
        Cleaned up the documentation and removed the PDF generation feature.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="remove">
        Removed the Release Notes document. This document now serves as the single source for release changes.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.0" date="2011-02-10" description="This is a maintenance release of the Catalog Ingest Tool.">
      <action dev="mcayanan, hyunlee" type="update" issue="PDSEN-256">
        Update the tool to be compatible with version 3.X.X of the Product Tools Library.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix" issue="PDSEN-326">
        Support apostrophe characters in author's names during reference validation.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix" issue="PDSEN-327">
        During reference validation, do a more robust checking of possible REFERENCE_KEY_ID values within square brackets inside a description.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix" issue="PDSEN-328">
        Support space characters in author's names during reference validation.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix" issue="PDSEN-333">
        Perform a proper comparison between two Set values. Fixed as the result of fixing PDSEN-332 for the product-tools project.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix" issue="PDSEN-334">
        No longer look for "AND" when determining if a REFERENCE_KEY_ID value denotes multiple authors.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix" issue="PDSEN-337">
        Perform string manipulation when matching values during referential integrity checking.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Corrected an issue ingesting the VOLUME catalog file when NODE_ID, ON_LINE_NAME, ON_LINE_IDENTIFICATION, and PROTOCOL_TYPE keywords are absent.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2010-01-05" description="This is the official release of the Catalog Ingest Tool.">
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added the capability to automatically ingest new standard values into the database.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added the capability to report references found in descriptions that do not match a REFERENCE_KEY_ID value within the same catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added an include path, '-i', command line flag option for validate mode to search for referenced catalog files.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added the capability to recursively traverse a target directory.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added a local, '-L', command line flag option to turn off directory recursion.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Removed volume referential integrity checking.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Support handling of multiple values when doing referential integrity checking.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Disabled following pointers in compare mode.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Removed reporting of severity levels in the compare report.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Updated the compare report to report messages in alphabetical order, according to the file name.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update">
        Updated the ingestion to report an error for lines greater than 80 characters instead of truncating it.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update">
        Updated the ingestion to ingest the DESCRIPTION statement instead of the RESOURCE_DESC statement in a dshousekeeping catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="update">
        Updated the ingestion to ignore pointer validation.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to report an error if the database name specified on the command-line is invalid.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to do a more complete check for missing keywords in a software catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an ingestion error when a REFERENCE_KEY_ID statement is missing in a reference catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an ingestion error when a REFERENCE_KEY_ID statement is missing in a dataset collections catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an ingestion error if a dataset collections catalog file is missing a DATA_SET_COLL_ASSOC_DATA_SETS object.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to do a more complete check for missing keywords when ingesting an 'nssdcdsid' catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an ingestion error when a MEDIUM_TYPE statement is missing in an inventory catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to ingest all INVENTORY_DATA_SET_INFO objects in an inventory catalog file instead of just the last one.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to do a more complete check for missing keywords when ingesting an instrument catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to report a missing INSTRUMENT_HOST_REFERENCE_INFO when ingesting an instrument host catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to do a more complete check for missing keywords and objects when ingesting a dataset catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an error when DATA_SET_ID is missing when ingesting a dataset catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to no longer check for a TARGET_REFERENCE_INFORMATION object when ingesting a target catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an error when TARGET_NAME is missing when ingesting a target catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to be able to support ingestion of multiple TARGET objects in a single target catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to ignore the PDS_AFFILIATION statement when ingesting a personnel catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an error if PDS_USER_ID is missing when ingesting a personnel catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an error when DATA_SET_ID or NODE_ID is missing when ingesting a dshousekeeping catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to throw an error when DATA_SET_ID or RELEASE_ID is missing when ingesting a dsrelease catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed the tool to be able to ingest multiple DATA_SET_RELEASE records in a dsrelease catalog file.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="fix">
        Fixed a bug where the tool had problems ingesting all files in a target directory.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix">
        Fixed a bug dealing with REFERENCE_KEY_ID values that contain multiple authors like PUTZIGANDMELLON2007. The tool was not correctly matching the start of the REFERENCE_DESC value with the first author listed in the associated REFERENCE_KEY_ID value.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix">
        Fixed a bug found in the compare report, where it would mark a pair of files as 'SAME' and report a warning, while marking another pair of files as 'DIFFERENT' and report the same type of warning message.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.4.0" date="2009-10-11" description="This fourth release of the Catalog Ingest Tool is intended for beta testing by the PDS Technical Staff.">
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added a "-c, --config" command line flag option to pass in a configuration file.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added an "-a, --alias" command line flag option to enable aliasing in the validate mode.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Validate only files with a .CAT extension when passing in a target directory to the tool.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Changed message severity level to INFO for REFERENCE_DESC values not beginning with the author name from the associated REFERNCE_KEY_ID value.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Changed message severity level to INFO for REFERENCE_KEY_ID values in a REF.CAT not being found in a non-REF.CAT.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Removed a referential integrity check to see if PDS_USER_ID and NODE_ID in a PERSON.CAT file exists in a non-PERSON.CAT file.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Updated the "allrefs" command line flag option to "-A".
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.3.0" date="2009-08-25" description="This third release of the Catalog Ingest Tool is intended for beta testing at the Engineering Node.">
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added the capability to find new standard values in validate mode.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added a complete referential integrity check in validate mode.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix">
        Fixed reference validation to support REFERENCE_KEY_ID values that are not made up of an author and year field.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix">
        Fixed various minor reporting issues to the compare function based on beta testing at the Engineering Node.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.2.0" date="2009-06-08" description="This second release of the Catalog Ingest Tool is intended for beta testing at the Engineering Node.">
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added the capability to do validation of catalog files.
      </action>
      <action dev="hyunlee" type="add">
        Added the capability to ingest catalog files into the PDS central catalog database.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added referential integrity checking of references.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Updated compare function to show a UNIX diff-like output for differences between the source and target.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="update">
        Updated command-line flag options with a "-m" or "--mode" flag. This enables the compare, ingest, or validate mode.
      </action>
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="fix">
        Fix the compare function to provide better support in comparing objects between the source and target.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.0" date="2009-04-03" description="This first release of the Catalog Ingest Tool is intended for beta testing at the Engineering Node.">
      <action dev="mcayanan" type="add">
        Added the capability to compare a catalog file with another catalog file or a directory of catalog files with another directory.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
