<ui:UiBinder xmlns:ui="urn:ui:com.google.gwt.uibinder"
			 xmlns:g="urn:import:com.google.gwt.user.client.ui">

  <g:HTMLPanel ui:field="welcomeBox" styleName="welcome">
  	<g:HTMLPanel ui:field="closeBtn" styleName="closeButton"></g:HTMLPanel>
    <h1>Welcome! Here's How to Get Started.</h1>
    <h2>About LACE</h2>
    <p>LACE is a tool for editing PDS4 label files and other XML files, developed by the
    User Centered Design group at NASA Ames Research Center. The User Centered Design
    group is a function of NASA's Planetary Data System.</p>
    
    <h2>The Label Manager</h2>
    <p>This screen is the Label Manager which list the labels you have created or imported.
    From here you can resume editing any of your labels, or delete labels you no longer
    need. To edit a label, click on the label name.</p>
    <p>All your labels are stored on the LACE server. Whenever you make changes while
    editing a label, those changes are stored on the LACE server, so you will never
    lose your work by accidentally closing your browser.</p>
    
    <h2>Importing and Exporting Labels</h2>
    <p>To edit an existing label from that is on your computer you must import the
    file into LACE. This sends the file to the LACE server. All editing changes are
    stored on the server. Your local file is not modified.</p>
    <p>If you want to get the
    latest version of the label from the server to your local computer, you must
    export the label file. First begin editing the label by clicking on the label
    name. Then press the Export Label button at the top of the screen.</p>
    
    <h2>Local Schema and Schematron Files</h2>
    <p>LACE supports local data dictionary XML Schema and Schematron files.
    Several released discipline-specific schemas are already available in LACE.
    To add more XML Schema or Schematron files, you can specify them when creating a
    new label or importing an existing label file.</p>
    
    <p class="bigInstruction">When you're ready, click the Create New Label button or the
    Import Existing Label button above to start editing&#160;your&#160;first&#160;label.</p>
  </g:HTMLPanel>

</ui:UiBinder>