<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2011, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology 
  Transfer at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Description 2.0.0</title>
    <author email="Sean.Hardman@jpl.nasa.gov">Sean Hardman</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Release Description 2.0.0">
      <p>This release of the PDS 2010 System represents Build 2a and is intended as an operational release of the system components to date. The following sections can be found in this document:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li><a href="#Reference_Documents">Reference Documents</a></li>
        <li><a href="#Capabilities">Capabilities</a></li>
        <li><a href="#Liens">Liens</a></li>
        <li><a href="#System_Requirements">System Requirements</a></li>
        <li><a href="#InstallationOperation">Installation/Operation</a></li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Reference Documents">
      <p>This section details the controlling and applicable documents referenced for this release. The controlling documents are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) Level 1, 2 and 3 Requirements, March 26, 2010.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) 2010 Project Plan, February 2010.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) 2010 System Architecture Specification, Version 1.2, May 25, 2011.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) 2010 Operations Concept, February 2010.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) General System Software Requirements Document (SRD), Version 1.0, June 11, 2011.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) Harvest Tool Software Requirements and Design Document (SRD/SDD), Version 1.0, June 12, 2011.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) Preparation Tools Software Requirements and Design Document (SRD/SDD), Version 0.1, October 6, 2010.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) Registry Service Software Requirements and Design Document (SRD/SDD), Version 1.0, June 12, 2011.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) Report Service Software Requirements and Design Document (SRD/SDD), Version 1.0, June 12, 2011.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) Search Service Software Requirements and Design Document (SRD/SDD), Version 0.4, June 12, 2011.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) Search Protocol, Version 0.2, October 17, 2011.</li>
        <li>Planetary Data System (PDS) Security Service Software Requirements and Design Document (SRD/SDD), Version 1.0, June 11, 2011.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The applicable documents are as follows:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>NASA Planetary Data System (PDS) 2010 System Build I Test Plan</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Capabilities">
      <p>This section details the new, modified and corrected capabilities that comprise this release. They are summarized here for a system-level view. A more detailed list of capabilities can be found in the release notes and change logs for each component.
      </p>

      <subsection name="New Capabilities">
        <p>The following capabilities are new for this release:
        </p>

        <ul>
					<li>Search Service is new for this release and includes the PDS search protocol request handler and generation of the search index from a populated Registry Service.
					</li>
          <li>Registry User Interface includes new support for browsing associations, packages, services, events, schemes, and classification nodes.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Modified Capabilities">
        <p>The following capabilities have been modified for this release:
        </p>

        <ul>
					<li>Registry Service was modified to include schema creation scripts for the target database and now requires a database population step during configuration.
					</li>
          <li>Harvest Tool was modified to represent LIDVID-based references as slots instead of associations as well as modified to keep pace with changes occurring in the PDS4 data model and the Registry Service interface.
          </li>
          <li>Validate Tool was modified to include the latest set of generic schemas generated from the data model.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Corrected Capabilities">
        <p>The following capabilities were corrected in this release:
        </p>

				<ul>
					<li>Registry User Interface was modified to correct scrolling issues and window behavior.
					</li>
					<li>Harvest Tool was modified to correct an issue where the directory path was not determined correctly for document products.
					</li>
				</ul>
      </subsection>
    </section>

    <section name="Liens">
      <p>This section details the liens against the capabilities that have yet to be implemented or are partially implemented. They are summarized here for a system-level view. A more detailed list of liens can be found in the release notes for each component.
      </p>

      <ul>
				<li>Complete development of the Catalog Ingest Tool supporting ingestion of PDS3 catalog files into the PDS4 registry.
				</li>
				<li>Add support for XML Schema 1.1 to the Validate Tool.
				</li>
				<li>Upgrade the Data Search interface to remove the dependence on the PDS3 catalog database.
				</li>
        <li>Need to expand the Registry User Interface to support updating status and single product registration.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="System Requirements">
      <p>This section details the system requirements for installing and operating the software. Specific system requirements for each component in this release can be found in their respective Installation documents.
      </p>

      <subsection name="Java Runtime Environment">
        <p>The custom software contained in this release was developed using Java and will run on any platform with a supported Java Runtime Environment (JRE). The software was specifically developed under Java version 1.6 and has only been tested with this version. The following commands test the local Java installation in a UNIX-based environment:
        </p>

        <source>
% which java
/usr/bin/java

% java -version
java version "1.6.0_26"
Java(TM) SE Runtime Environment (build 1.6.0_26-b03-384-10M3425)
Java HotSpot(TM) 64-Bit Server VM (build 20.1-b02-384, mixed mode)
        </source>

        <p>The first command above checks whether the <i>java</i> executable is in the environment's path and the second command reports the version. If Java is not installed or the version is not at least 1.6, Java will need to be downloaded and installed in the current environment. Consult the local system administrator for installation of this software. For the do-it-yourself crowd, the Java software can be downloaded from the <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/" target="_blank">Oracle Java Download</a> page. The software package of choice is the Java Standard Edition (SE) 6, either the JDK or the JRE package. The JDK package is not necessary to run the software but could be useful if development and compilation of Java software will also occur in the current environment.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Java Application Server">
        <p>The other main system requirement pertains to providing a Java application server for hosting certain components (Registry Service and Registry User Interface). The suggested application server for this release is Apache Tomcat with a minimal version of 6.0.20 through version 7.0.X. Consult the local system administrator for installation of this software. For the do-it-yourself crowd, the Apache Tomcat software can be downloaded from the <a href="http://tomcat.apache.org/" target="_blank">Apache Tomcat</a> page. Choose the version to download (6.0 or 7.0) from the menu on the left. Details on downloading, installing and configuring an Apache Tomcat server can be found in the <a href="index-tomcat.html">Tomcat Deployment</a> document.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>

    <section name="Installation/Operation">
      <p>This section details the installation and operation of the software in this release. This release is intended for deployment in the Engineering Node operations environment with certain components deployed in the environments of participating Nodes. Details regarding the release for each of these components, including installation of the packages and operation of the associated software, can be found in the documentation for each component. This release is comprised of the following components:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li><a href="../harvest/index.html">Harvest Tool</a> - 1.0.0</li>
        <li><a href="../preparation/index.html">Preparation Tools</a></li>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="../preparation/core/index.html">Core Library</a> - 0.4.0</li>
          <li><a href="../preparation/design/index.html">Design Tool</a> - 0.2.0</li>
          <li><a href="../preparation/generate/index.html">Generate Tool</a> - 0.2.0</li>
          <li><a href="../preparation/validate/index.html">Validate Tool</a> - 0.4.0</li>
        </ul>
        <li><a href="../registry/index.html">Registry</a></li>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="../registry/registry-service/index.html">Registry Service</a> - 1.0.0</li>
          <li><a href="../registry/registry-ui/index.html">Registry User Interface</a> - 1.0.0</li>
        </ul>
        <li><a href="../report/index.html">Report Service</a> - 1.0.0</li>
        <li><a href="../search/index.html">Search Service</a> - 0.1.0</li>
        <li><a href="../security/index.html">Security Service</a> - 1.0.0</li>
      </ul>

      <p>Not all of the above components are required for a given installation of the software for this release. The following sections detail typical deployment scenarios for the Engineering Node and the Discipline Nodes, respectively.
      </p>

      <subsection name="Engineering Node Environment">
        <p>This section details deployment to the Engineering Node operations environment. The following diagram details the deployment of the major components of this release and gives a very high-level view of the interfaces between the components and system resources:
        </p>

        <center>
          <a href="../images/en-deploy-2.0.0.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="EN Deployment" src="../images/en-deploy-2.0.0-scale.jpg" border="1" /></a><br/>
          If viewing this document in online form, click the image for a larger version.
        </center>

        <p>The following diagram depicts the EN system flow, starting with central catalog migration, data product registration and finishing up with search index generation:
        </p>

        <center>
          <a href="../images/en-system-flow-2.0.0.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="EN System Flow" src="../images/en-system-flow-2.0.0-scale.jpg" border="1" /></a><br/>
          If viewing this document in online form, click the image for a larger version.
        </center>

        <p>The components depicted above serve as the operational deployment of this release for the Engineering Node. The main purpose of this deployment is for demonstration and testing purposes.
        </p>

        <ul>
          <li><b>Registry Service</b><br/>
<!--
            <p>The Registry Service provides functionality for tracking, auditing, locating and maintaining artifacts within the system. For this release, the registry is populated with the PDS4 context products migrated from the PDS3 central catalog database. The web-based endpoint for this service is <a href="http://pdsops2.jpl.nasa.gov/services/registry/" target="_blank">http://pdsops2.jpl.nasa.gov/services/registry/</a>.
            </p>
-->
            <p>The Registry Service provides functionality for tracking, auditing, locating and maintaining artifacts within the system. For this release, the registry is populated with the PDS4 context products migrated from the PDS3 central catalog database.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Registry User Interface</b><br/>
<!--
            <p>The Registry User Interface provides a simple viewing capability of the contents of the associated Registry Service. It is intended to offer visual verification of successful registration of products. The web-based endpoint for this application is <a href="http://pdsops2.jpl.nasa.gov/services/registry-ui/" target="_blank">http://pdsops2.jpl.nasa.gov/services/registry-ui/</a>.
            </p>
-->
            <p>The Registry User Interface provides a simple viewing capability of the contents of the associated Registry Service. It is intended to offer visual verification of successful registration of products.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Search Service</b><br/>
            <p>The Search Service provides functionality for accepting queries from data consumers for registered products and includes functionality for retrieving search results. This component acts as the interface to the Registry Service for the data consumer.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Report Service</b><br/>
<!--
            <p>The Report Service provides the capability for capturing and reporting metrics. With this release and the previous release, this service is undergoing testing of configurations and features with a set of metrics from the Engineering Node and the Imaging Node at JPL. This service is not yet available to the user community. The web-based endpoint for this service is <a href="http://pdsops.jpl.nasa.gov/services/report/" target="_blank">http://pdsops.jpl.nasa.gov/services/report/</a>.
            </p>
-->
            <p>The Report Service provides the capability for capturing and reporting metrics. With this release and the previous release, this service is undergoing testing of configurations and features with a set of metrics from the Engineering Node and the Imaging Node at JPL. This service is not yet available to the user community.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Security Service</b><br/>
            <p>The Security Service provides authentication and authorization functions for the system. This service is satisfied with an open source directory service. The directory service is populated with the PDS personnel list extracted from the PDS3 central catalog database. The application server hosting the Registry Service and Registry User Interface is configured to restrict access to certain URLs and to forward those requests to this service for authentication and authorization.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Harvest Tool</b><br/>
            <p>The Harvest Tool provides the means for registering products with the Registry Service. This tool reads a PDS4 product label, extracts specified metadata and registers the product with the registry. This tool allows the user to register a batch of products and generates a summary report.
            </p>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Discipline Node Environment">
        <p>This section details the deployment to a participating Discipline Node environment. The Nodes are asked to download, install and exercise the software that makes up this release. The following diagram details an example deployment of selected components:
        </p>

        <center>
          <a href="../images/dn-deploy-2.0.0.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="DN Deployment" src="../images/dn-deploy-2.0.0-scale.jpg" border="1" /></a><br/>
          If viewing this document in online form, click the image for a larger version.
        </center>

        <p>The selected components depicted above are intended to aid the Nodes in their PDS3 to PDS4 conversion exercises. The following diagram depicts a normalized system flow, starting with schema design, continuing onto data product label generation and validation and finishing up with data product registration:
        </p>

        <center>
          <a href="../images/dn-system-flow-2.0.0.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="DN System Flow" src="../images/dn-system-flow-2.0.0-scale.jpg" border="1" /></a><br/>
          If viewing this document in online form, click the image for a larger version.
        </center>

        <p>This diagram identifies where the system components come into play within the system flow. These components and the ones depicted in the deployment diagram, are described in more detail with respect to how the components can be utilized in the PDS3 to PDS4 conversion exercises with an eye towards testing these components for use in operations:
        </p>

        <ul>
          <li><b>Design Tool</b><br/>
            <p>The Design Tool is intended to aid users in the development of their data product label schemas. This release identifies two off-the-shelf products (Oxygen and Eclipse) that are available for this purpose. The provided documentation guides the user with respect to the download, installation and operation of each of these products.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Generate Tool</b><br/>
            <p>The Generate Tool is intended to aid users in the generation of their data product labels. This tool was developed by the Imaging Node at JPL and provides a command-line interface for generating PDS4 Labels from either a PDS3 Label or a PDS-specific DOM object.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Validate Tool</b><br/>
            <p>The Validate Tool comes pre-packaged with the latest version of the generic schemas generated from the data model. The tool allows the user to validate collections of products or single products against the associated generic schema. Specific schemas can be passed into the tool to enable a more detailed validation check. Although the Design Tools listed above provide a file-by-file validation capability, this tool allows the user to validate a batch of products and generates a summary report.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Registry Service</b><br/>
            <p>The Registry Service provides functionality for tracking, auditing, locating and maintaining artifacts within the system. Ultimately, all products (including PDS3 products) will be registered and tracked with the Registry Service. For this release, users are asked to install and configure a local instance of the service in order to exercise this procedure. Additionally if the user is participating in the PDS3 to PDS4 conversion exercises, the resulting products or collections of products can be registered with their local registry instance.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Registry User Interface</b><br/>
            <p>The Registry User Interface provides a simple viewing capability of the contents of the associated Registry Service. It is intended to offer visual verification of successful registration of products.
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>Harvest Tool</b><br/>
            <p>The Harvest Tool provides the means for registering products with the Registry Service. This tool reads a PDS4 product label, extracts specified metadata and registers the product with the registry. This tool allows the user to register a batch of products and generates a summary report.
            </p>
          </li>
        </ul>

				<p>An installation exercise was not specified for this release but each Node is welcome to download, install and exercise the above components in their environment. The Installation document for the desired component(s) is a good place to get started.
				</p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
