<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Copyright 2010-2012, by the California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  Any commercial use must be negotiated with the Office of Technology Transfer
  at the California Institute of Technology.

  This software is subject to U. S. export control laws and regulations
  (22 C.F.R. 120-130 and 15 C.F.R. 730-774). To the extent that the software
  is subject to U.S. export control laws and regulations, the recipient has
  the responsibility to obtain export licenses or other export authority as
  may be required before exporting such information to foreign countries or
  providing access to foreign nationals.

  $Id$
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Changes</title>
    <author email="Paul.Ramirez@jpl.nasa.gov">Paul Ramirez</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="TBD" description="This release of the Registry Core is a component of the integrated release 2.2.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="fix">
        PDS-51: Updates to registry objects no longer overwrite key attributes when not provided by the client. Key attributes include home, lid, status, and versionName.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.0" date="2012-01-31" description="This release of the Registry Core is a component of the integrated release 2.1.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        PDS-41: Allow filtering by status.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        PDS-43: Registry client now supports an expanded set of registry objects. Namely, ExtrinsicObject, Association, Service, RegistryPackage, AuditableEvent, ClassificationScheme, and ClassificationNode.
      </action>
      <action dev="shardman" type="update">
        Cleaned up the documentation and removed the PDF generation feature.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2011-11-09" description="This release of the Registry Core is a component of the integrated release 2.0.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Added support for PostgreSQL.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        Ability to generate database schema from the model classes.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="fix">
        JSON serialization of Enums.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.2.0" date="2011-08-29" description="This release of the Registry Core is a component of the integrated release 1.2.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-14: Support to do package level operations such as delete and update status. In addition, allows for items to be published into a package.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        PDS-18: Updated RegistryClient to use RegistryObjects instead of low-level constructs. This will ease integration with outside tools.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-32: Added support for external link operations.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-39: Built in support for replication operations and report on ongoing replication.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        Enchanced Auditable Event end point to allow for better filtering. Now supports eventStart, eventEnd, and requestId.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        Refactored registry service interface and implementation to consolidate and remove redundant code. Publish and delete of all objects now go through single methods instead of one for each object.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="fix">
        Now throws an exception when looking up object versions of something that does not exist. Previously this returned null which caused problems upstream.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.0" date="2011-03-25" description="This release of the Registry Core is a component of the integrated release 1.1.0 of the PDS 2010 System.">
      <action dev="pramirez" type="fix">
        PDS-1: Delete associations when a registry object is removed.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-3: Ability to page through all services.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        PDS-7: Mapped Product to ExtrinsicObject to align better with information model for registry. Moved all interfaces that ended in product(s) to extrinsic(s).
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-8: Allow a set of Classifications to be associated with a given registry object.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-16: Configuration end point to pass in classification schemes and nodes as one XML file.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        PDS-17: Make associations based off their global identifier instead of the LIDVID.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-19: Defined RegistryPackage as an intrinsic object. Acts merely as a collection of registered objects through the use of Associations.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-20: Added ExternalIdentifier support for registered objects.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="add">
        PDS-22: Include delete operation for Classifications delete. 
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="update">
        Refactored model classes from the service classes to allow for the core to be included as a jar dependency.
      </action>
      <action dev="pramirez" type="fix">
        Set the object type for all intrinsic objects.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
